Guide to the National Organization for Women, New York City Chapter (NOW-NYC) Records TAM.106
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: Administration, 1966-2011; 1971-2002; 13.08 Linear Feet in 25 manuscript boxes, a half manuscript box, and 3 oversized flat boxes
  - General Membership Minutes, 2002 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - "Growing Your Grassroots" - Membership Recruitment and Retention, undated (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Guidelines for NOW-NYC Advisory Council, undated (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Guidelines for NOW-NYC Center, 1973 (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Handwritten Notes, 1978-1979, 1983-1985, undated (Box 54, Folder 18-19)
  - Handwritten Notes -- Presidential Reports, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - History and About NOW from 1987-1990, 1997 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - History and About NOW: Major Accomplishments, 1966-1986 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - History and About NOW-NYC, 1969-1974, 1984, 1992, 1996, 1999-2002 (Box 55, Folder 2-3)
  - How To Get Involved with NOW-NYC Committees, undated (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Interns, 2002 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Job Descriptions, 1972, 1977-1979, 1985, circa 2000s (Box 2, Folder 21, Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Leases and Permits, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Litigation Policy, 1968, 1972, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Marisa Lo Blanco (Administrative Director) -- Workplans, 2002-2003 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Member Talent Bank Forms, undated (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Membership, 1981, 1983, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Memorandum, 1967-2002 (Box 56, Folder 1-3)
  - Monthly Newsletter of the Administrative Vice President, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - "National Strength Through Chapter Development", 1979 (Box 153, Folder 20)
  - Newsletter, 1969, 1971, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 23, Box 56, Folder 5)
  - NOW Center Guidelines, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - NOW Comprehensive Administrative Manual, circa 2002 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - NOWMed Brochure, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - NOW-NY: A Case Study by Jennifer Smith, 1980 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - NOW-NYC Elections, 1971-1979, 1983-1985, 2000-2003, undated (Box 56, Folder 9, Box 57, Folder 1-2)
  - NOW-NYC Move and Renovations, 1984 (Box 57, Folder 3, Box 153, Folder 1)
  - NOW-NYC New York Police Department Surveillance Dossier, 1971 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - The NOW York Woman Newspaper -- Administrative Papers, 1979, 1982 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Notes, Drafts, and Research for March/April NOW-NYC Newsletter, 2002 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Notes, Drafts, and Research for May/June NOW-NYC Newsletter, 2002 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Office Information, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Open House Week, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Organizational Charts of NOW-NYC, undated (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Parliamentary Procedure, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Personnel Policies, 1979 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Phonebank Policies and Procedures, undated (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Practicing What We Preach - The National Organizers Alliance Report on Policies and Practices of Justice Organizations, 2001 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  - Press Conference Talking Points, 2002 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Press Contacts and Directories, 1985-1986 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, 1971-1972, 1974, 1978-1979 (Box 58, Folder 3-7)
  - Press Releases, 1980-1989 (Box 58, Folder 8-16)
  - Press Releases, 1990-1998 (Box 58, Folder 17, Box 59, Folder 1-8)
  - Press Releases, 2000-2002 (Box 104, Folder 11, Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, 2000-2011 (Box 59, Folder 9-19)
  - Press Releases, undated (Box 59, Folder 20-21, Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases -- Announcing NOW's Formation, 1966 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Proclamations, 1970 (Box 60, Folder 3, Box 154, Folder 1)
  - Program Evaluations, 1985-1987 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Program Proposal, 1984 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Public Relations Kit, 1983-1984 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - Recruitment, 1976, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Referrals, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Resumes, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Speakers Bureau, 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 6-7, Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Speeches, 1972, 1992, 1994, circa 2000s (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Suggestions for Standing Committees, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Tabling Guidelines, undated (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Telephone Surveys, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Unity Team Meeting Agendas, 2002 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Volunteer Orientation Material, circa 1980s (Box 60, Folder 13)
  - whatNOW Newsletters, 2005-2011 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - What We Do (NOW-NYC Promotional Video), undated; TW_TAM_106_ER_11
- Series II: Correspondence, 1965-2003; 5.25 Linear Feet in 12 manuscript boxes
  Scope and Content Note
  General correspondence that does not pertain to specific committees are located in this series. This series includes correspondence between NOW-NYC members; NOW-NYC, politicians, and legislative bodies; NOW-NYC and affiliated organizations; NOW-NYC and the media; NOW-NYC and legal defense groups; and women seeking NOW-NYC's support in addressing sexual discrimination cases. This series also includes Muriel Fox's historic 1966 press release announcing the formation of NOW; material pertaining to the debate between NOW and Anne Grant over the holder of the copyright for the 1972 slide presentation for Our North American Foremothers, found in the 1973 folders; and correspondence documenting the internal controversy that took place at the NOW National Conference in New Orleans in December 1974, which are located in the 1975 folders.
  General correspondence in this series is arranged chronologically. Correspondence with specific subjects are arranged alphabetically.
  - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 9, Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 10, Box 61, Folder 7-10)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 11, Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12, Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 13, Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 63, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 63, Folder 4-5, Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 64, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 64, Folder 4-5, Box 65, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 65, Folder 3-6)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 66, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 66, Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 66, Folder 6, Box 67, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 67, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 68, Folder 9-11, Box 69, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 69, Folder 3-4)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 69, Folder 5-6)
  - Correspondence -- Contributions, 1977-1979 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Legislators, 1967-1988, 1992-1995, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 2-4)
  - Correspondence -- Jennifer K. Brown, 1983-1985 (Box 70, Folder 5-7)
  - Correspondence -- NOW Action Center, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence -- Requests for NOW-NYC Materials, 1978-1979 (Box 71, Folder 2)
- Series III: Officers' Files, 1971-2003; 3.5 Linear Feet in 8 manuscript boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains materials realted to former presidents of NOW-NYC: Jean Faust, Elayne Snyder, Noreen Connell, and Matthea Marquart.
  - Subseries III.A: Jean Faust, 1966-1970; 0.88 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes
    Jean Faust served as NOW-NYC's first president in 1967. Notable in her papers is information on the action taken against Colgate-Palmolive in 1967 for discriminatory hiring practices. The demonstration included NOW-NYC members Flo Kennedy, Jacqui Ceballos, and Kate Millet, all of whom led a "flush-in" in front of company headquarters in New York, dumping the company's products into a commode on Park Avenue. Also included are files on the 1967 New York State Constitutional Convention where NOW demanded many legislative changes to promote equality of opportunity in education, employment, and housing. Materials on the actions to desegregate the classified advertisements of the New York Times appear here as well. Other materials include announcements, bylaws, correspondence, flyers, mailing lists, meeting notices, print media articles, and reports.
    Files are arranged alphabetically by topic.
    - Jean Faust -- Abortion, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Jean Faust -- Bylaws, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Jean Faust -- Colgate-Palmolive, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Jean Faust -- Constitutional Convention -- Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Jean Faust -- Constitutional Convention -- Delegates, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Jean Faust -- Constitutional Convention -- Statements (on #449 and #450), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Jean Faust -- Constitutional Convention -- Proposals, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Jean Faust -- Correspondence (April-August 1967), 1967-24685 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Jean Faust -- Correspondence (Sept.-Dec. 1967) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Jean Faust -- Correspondence, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Jean Faust -- Correspondence, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Jean Faust -- Correspondence, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Jean Faust -- Education Report -- Kate Millet, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Jean Faust -- Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) Correspondence -- Classified Ad Project, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Jean Faust -- Employment Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Jean Faust -- Equal Rights for Indian Women, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Jean Faust -- First Officers, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Jean Faust -- Henrietta Levenson, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Jean Faust -- Human Rights -- NY State Governor's Commission, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Jean Faust -- Image of Women in Media, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Jean Faust -- Information Packet, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Jean Faust -- Legislation, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Jean Faust -- Legislative -- Political, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Jean Faust -- Mailing List, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Jean Faust -- Meeting Notices, Minutes, etc., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Jean Faust -- NOW-NY on Radio and TV, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Jean Faust -- Office of Federal Contract Compliance (OFCC), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Jean Faust -- Pauline Dziob Case, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Jean Faust -- Pauline Sharfstein, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Jean Faust -- Print Media Articles, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Jean Faust -- Reports, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Jean Faust -- Sex Education, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Subseries III.B: Elayne Snyder, 1971-1982; 2.19 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes
    Elayne Snyder was president of NOW-NYC in 1974. At that time, NOW-NYC sponsored a series of programs to celebrate women in the arts, which were held at Town Hall in 1974. Her papers contain materials from most of the committees active at this time period, as well as administrative records from the Executive Committee and National NOW. Other materials include announcements, brochures, correspondence, programs, flyers, minutes, and position statements.
    - Elayne Snyder -- Ad Hoc Committees, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Advisory Council, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Advisory Council, 1975-1976 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Arts, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Board of Directors, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Chair of NOW-NYC Board of Directors, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Child Care, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Correspondence, 1971-1972, 1975, 1982 (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Education, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Education, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Election Procedure, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Employment Committee, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Employment, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Employment, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Executive Vice President of NOW-NYC, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Elayne Snyder -- The Feminist Spirit, 1977 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Fundraising, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Fundraising, Feminist Community, and Public Relations, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Elayne Snyder -- "God Bless God" Play, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Health, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Image, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Image, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Image Committee, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Image Committee, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Image -- National Ad Campaign, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Legislative Committee, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Legislative and Political, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Letters, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Elayne Snyder -- The Liberated Woman's Appointment Book, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Majority Report, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Marriage and Divorce Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Marriage and Divorce, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Membership, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Membership Committee Coordinator, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Membership Meetings, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Elayne Snyder -- National NOW, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Newsletter Committee, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Elayne Snyder -- President of NOW-NYC, 1974 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Programs, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Psychology, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Rape Prevention Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Reproduction and its Control, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Sachem Fund Project, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Sexuality and Lesbianism, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Speeches, 1974 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Sports, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Elayne Snyder -- Town Hall Series, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Subseries III.C: Noreen Connell, 1968-1972; 0.44 Linear Feet in a manuscript box
    Noreen Connell was president of NOW-NYC from 1977-1978. Materials in this subseries date from the late 1960s and early 1970s, at the inception of the women's movement, and are not limited to NOW. The bulk of her papers include position papers on various topics such as pregnancy, abortion, and sexuality; material on other women's liberation groups, such as Red Stockings and Women's Liberation; and correspondence and poetry. Publications from the early women's movement have been separated and are to be catalogued with Tamiment periodicals.
    - Noreen Connell -- Canadian Women, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Noreen Connell -- Consumerism, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Noreen Connell -- Cuba, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Noreen Connell -- "Defining Reality", 1969 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Noreen Connell -- "False Consciousness", 1969 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Noreen Connell -- International Women's Day, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Noreen Connell -- Jewish Women, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Noreen Connell -- Labor, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Noreen Connell -- Lesbians, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Noreen Connell -- Male Chauvinism, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Noreen Connell -- Media Women, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Noreen Connell -- Miss America Contest, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Noreen Connell -- Monographs, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Noreen Connell -- Poetry and Songs, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Noreen Connell -- Radical Feminists 28, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Noreen Connell -- RAT, 1968-1972 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Noreen Connell -- "Resistance to Consciousness", 1969 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Noreen Connell -- Red Stockings Rap, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Noreen Connell -- Self Defense, [1970] (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Noreen Connell -- "Women and their Bodies" Lectures, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Noreen Connell -- Women in the Professions, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Noreen Connell -- "A Woman Scientist Speaks", 1969 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Noreen Connell -- Women's Liberation, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Noreen Connell -- Women's Liberation Center, 1970-1972 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Subseries III.D: Matthea Marquart, 2000-2003; 0.44 Linear Feet in a legal manuscript box
    Matthea Marquart served as president of NOW-NYC from 2002-2003. Prior to becoming President, she served as the Director of Development from 2000-2002, the Chair of the Board of Directors for the Service Fund of NOW-NYC from 2002-2003, and a Board Member of the Service Fund of NOW-NYC from 2001-2002. Materials include administrative papers, materials related to Marquart's NOW-NYC Presidential campaign, memorandum, speeches, business cards, and her name tag.
    - Matthea Marquart -- Administrative, 2000, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Matthea Marquart -- Articles About, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Matthea Marquart -- Business Cards, undated (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Matthea Marquart -- Election Flyer, 2001; TW_TAM_106_ER_1
    - Matthea Marquart -- Memorandum, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Matthea Marquart -- Name Tag, undated (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Matthea Marquart -- NOW-NYC Presidential Campaign, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Matthea Marquart -- Speeches and Talking Points, 2002-2003 (Box 72, Folder 8)
- Series IV: Committees, 1966-2006; 1970-2002; 19.58 Linear Feet in 41 manuscript boxes, a flat box, 3 oversized flat boxes, and 2 flat-file-folders
  Materials in this series include information packets with brochures, fact sheets, pamphlets, and guides; subject files with research materials and news clippings; memorandum and handwritten notes; meeting minutes and agendas; correspondence; event flyers and posters; press releases; directories, bylaws, and committee specific administrative documents; and conference materials. Specific information about committees and the materials have been provided, when available.
  The Ad Hoc Committees consist of Artists, Writers, and Musicians; Sports; Women and Health; Women and Poverty; the Women and Volunteerism Task Force; and XYZ. Materials related to these committees consist of press releases, promotional statements, correspondence, event flyers, questionnaires, resources, fact sheets, and announcements.
  Arts Committee: This committee's goal was to promote women in the fine and performing arts. The group's members were painters, sculptors, actors, poets, and artists of other media. Materials related to this committee include correspondence, minutes, schedules, posters, flyers, and a telephone tree. (See also the Non Print (NP) Collection, which includes a photo reproduction of an ink wash "Babbling Brook" (1966) by Zalmar, the first committee chair, and an 8" x 10" poster for a NOW gala in 1974, featuring Alice Neel's well-known portrait of Linda Nochlin and her daughter. NP folder contains a photograph and numerous flyers and programs by and about women in the arts.)
  Bicentennial Committee: The goal of this committee was to celebrate the history of women and their contributions to American history during America's bicentennial in 1975. Materials related to this committee include correspondence, notes, and research materials.
  Bylaws Committee: This committee was formed to review the bylaws amendment process. Materials related to this committee include notes, copies of NOW-NYC bylaws, proposals for amendments to the bylaws, memorandum, minutes, and draft bylaws.
  Campaign 2004 Committee: This committee was anti-President George W. Bush and focused on the 2004 Presidential election. Materials related to this committee include fact sheets and event flyers.
  Child Care Committee: From 1969 to 1971, this committee was run as a National Task Force and in 1971, it became the NOW-New York Child Care Committee. Materials related to this committee include correspondence, reports, event flyers, a newsletter, position statements, and speeches.
  Consciousness Raising Committee: This committee organized consciousness raising groups to provide a supportive atmosphere for women to discover their common bonds; and to learn more about themselves and each other. Materials related to this committee include brochures, clippings, correspondence, descriptive literature, event flyers, meeting minutes, memorandum, reports, and members lists.
  Domestic Relations Committee: Materials related to this committee include a membership directory, notes, press releases, correspondence, agendas, fact sheets, memorandums, resources, and event flyers.
  Education Committee: In 1970, this committee protested gender stereotypes on the children's television show Sesame Street by threatening to boycott the show's sponsor, General Foods, and won. The bulk of the materials from 1971 consists of surveys about educational opportunities for girls and boys in the New York City junior high and high schools, which resulted in the widely-circulated "Report on Sex Bias in the Public Schools." This committee also monitored the enforcement of Title IX, outlawing sex discrimination in educational institutions and reviewed the New York City school system's progress in eliminating discrimination. Most of the materials from 1972 focus on NOW-NYC's Education Action Conference. Other materials related to this committee include agendas, brochures, correspondence, legal documents, minutes, reports, speakers' lists, bibliographies, event flyers, press releases, memorandum, subject files, and surveys.
  Employment Committee: In 1972, the Employment Committee charged the American Broadcasting Company (ABC), Clairol, and General Mills of discriminatory hiring practices and correspondence documenting these allegations appear in this committee's folders. In 1973, this committee produced the "Report on Sex Discrimination in Employment Agencies"; and acted as an employment agency for its members and received numerous job listings from corporations. Materials related to this committee include subject files, clippings, correspondence, depositions, press releases, meeting announcements, employment resources, event flyers, fact sheets, job postings, and legislation about sex discrimination in the work place.